

HAFIDH SYAHPUTRA

Quality Assurance

+6289667887044 hafidhsyahputra99@gmail.com Yogyakarta



PROFILE

I am a quality assurance person highly experienced in software testing. I have managed to get the software to pass due diligence using various methods so that no bugs are detected in production. Accustomed to generating Test Case scenarios and locating faults in the website and API.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• PT Javan Cipta Solusi | February 2024 - Until Now

Quality Assurance Engineer

Javan is a business providing services related to information technology. This company offers services for product development, training, and software design. What I do:

- 1. Create test case using QATouch
- 2. Familiar with Agile frameworks scrum
- 3. Understand the testing stages in SDLC
- 4. Using tools management Taiga, Openproject
- 5. Create automated testing Selenium JS

• PLN Icon Plus | September 2023 - December 2023

Quality Assurance Engineer - Internship

ICON+ is an Indonesian firm that provides Internet solution provider and software development services to State Electricity Companies. I use automation to assist with UMS (User Management System) software testing. What I do:

- 1. Create testing documentation
- 2. Familiar with Agile frameworks scrum
- 3. Create automated testing Cypress

PT Qatros Teknologi Nusantara | February 2023 - June 2023

Quality Assurance Engineer - MSIB Kampus Merdeka Batch 4 - Internship

Qatros is a digital needs service that offers services like public training, bootcamp training, and customized home training in addition to consultation, development, and application maintenance. What I do:

- 1. Create testing documentation
- 2. Familiar with Agile frameworks scrum
- 3. Create automated testing Selenium Ruby
- 4. Create a testing report

• PT Cerdas Digital Nusantara | August 2020 - December 2022

Quality Assurance

Cakap is a technology education application development startup from Indonesia that focuses on bold, two-way education. What I do:

- 1. Manual testing of the functionality and usability of mobile apps and web apps in staging and beta phases
- 2. Create a bug discovery report and use Jira
- 3. Familiar with Agile frameworks scrum
- 4. Understand the testing stages in SDLC

EDUCATION

2020 - 2024

Technical Information

Universitas Teknologi Digital Indonesia

I studied at the Indonesian Digital Technology University (previous STMIK AKAKOM) and take Technical.

Information Major.

SKILLS

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Leadership
- Problem-solving capabilities
- Creativity
- Critical Thinking
- Time and project management

Technical Skills

- Testing Tools : Selenium WebDriver, Cypress, Katalon
- · Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, Java
- · Performance Testing: JMeter
- Database: MySQL

ORGANISATIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2023 - Until Now

Padukuhan Salakan Youth

Publication/Decoration/Documentation

August 2021 - August 2023

Informatics and Computers UKM

Education Division Coordinator

April 2019 - June 2022

Salakan Organization

Leader